Office of the Associate Vice-President, Academic fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- University matters - correspondence, 1983 - 1998; F-201-1; 1.96 m of textual records
  - Vice-President, Harbour Centre and Continuing Studies, 1986 - 1994; F-201-1-3; 7 cm of textual records
    - Matching funds, 1991 - 1992; F-201-1-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-13)
    - VP Harbour Centre and Continuing Studies, 1994; F-201-1-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-13)
  - Vice-President, Research, 1985 - 1997; F-201-1-4; 21 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with the Vice-President, Research / Information Systems (renamed VP Research in 1990), and with departments which belonged to the VP Research reporting portfolio. Activities and topics documented include development of the university's computing polices and administrative computing systems; the AVP Academic's interactions with the University Archives and the Centre for Systems Science; and the activities and deliberations of a number of university committees, including the Cognitive Science Program Steering Committee, the Computing Advisory Committee, the Administrative Information Systems Steering Committee, the Committee on Instructional Computing, and the Archives and Records Management Committee. Records include correspondence, reports, meeting agenda and minutes, presentations, and policies.
    Computing Advisory Committee; Office of the Vice-President, Research; Cognitive Science Program Steering Committee; Administrative Information Systems Steering Committee; Advisory Committee for Archives and Records Management; Committee on Instructional Computing; Centre for Systems Science; Archives and Records Management Department
    Further accruals to the sub-series are expected.
    - Computer Advisory Committee, 1985 - 1988; F-201-1-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-13)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.9.
    - Research Council, 1986; F-201-1-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-13)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.12.
    - Administrative Information System Steering Committee, 1986 - 1988; F-201-1-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-13)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.11.
    - Mircrocomputer lab, 1986 - 1988; F-201-1-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-14)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.13.
    - Cognitive Science Program, 1986 - 1989; F-201-1-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-14)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.10.
    - Personnel / Payroll systems, vol. 1, 1986 - 1989; F-201-1-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-14)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.11.a.
    - Personnel / Payroll systems, vol. 2, 1986 - 1989; F-201-1-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-14)
    - Archives Committee, 1986 - 1991; F-201-1-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-14)
    - VP Research and Information Systems - general, 1987 - 1991; F-201-1-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-14)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.1.
    - Centre for Systems Science, 1988 - 1991; F-201-1-4-0-10 (Archival box - standard 201-14)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.7.
    - Committee on Instructional Computing, vol. 1, 1989 - 1991; F-201-1-4-0-11 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.2.
    - Committee on Instructional Computing, vol. 2, 1989 - 1991; F-201-1-4-0-12 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
    - Committee on Instructional Computing, vol. 3, 1989 - 1991; F-201-1-4-0-13 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
    - VP Research - general, 1992 - 1997; F-201-1-4-0-14 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.D.1.
  - Vice-President, Finance and Administration, 1988 - 1997; F-201-1-5; 5 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of the Associate Vice-President, Academic's correspondence with the Vice-President, Financial Services (renamed VP Finance and Administration in 1994). Activities and topics documented include capital and operating budget planning, policy development, and use of contingency funds. Records include correspondence and policies.
    Office of the Vice-President, Finance and Administration
    For other records in this fonds relating to university finances and budget, see:
    F-201-2, Finanical matters - general (1985-1996).
    - VP Financial Services - general, 1988 - 1989; F-201-1-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.F.
    - VP Financial Services, 1990 - 1991; F-201-1-5-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-69)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.F.1.
    - VP Financial Services, 1992 - 1993; F-201-1-5-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
      Creator's original file classification code: 1.E.
    - VP Finance and Administration, 1994 - 1997; F-201-1-5-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
- Financial matters - correspondence, 1985 - 1996; F-201-2; 29 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to university finances and budget planning. Activities include allocation of departmental operating and capital budgets for units within the VP Academic's reporting portfolio; university funding requests under the provincial government's Funds for Excellence in Education (FEE) program; and budget reduction planning in 1995-1996. Records include correspondence and reports; capital equipment, renovation, and operating budget requests, proposals and authorizations; budget estimates and working papers; and university five-year capital plans.
  The arrangement of the material into sub-series is based on the original file classification system used by the creator to organize the records. Files are arranged chronologically.
  No further accruals to the series or any of its sub-series are expected.
  Sub-series descriptions are not available. File lists are available.
  - Capital budget, 1986 - 1996; F-201-2-1; 20 cm of textual records
    - Instructional Use of Information Technology (CSIL), vol. 1, 1986 - 1988; F-201-2-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
      Creator's original file classification code: 2.A.7.
    - Instructional Use of Information Technology (CSIL), vol. 2, 1986 - 1988; F-201-2-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-15)
    - Capital equipment budget, vol. 1, 1987 - 1988; F-201-2-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-16)
      Creator's original file classification code: 2.A.5.
    - Capital equipment budget, vol. 2, 1987 - 1988; F-201-2-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-16)
    - Five-year plan, 1987 - 1988; F-201-2-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-16)
      Creator's original file classification code: 2.A.4.
    - Capital budget - general, 1988; F-201-2-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-16)
      Creator's original file classification code: 2.A.1.
    - Information to Deans / Department request submissions, 1988; F-201-2-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-16)
      Creator's original file classification code: 2.A.3.
    - Capital budget - general, 1989 - 1990; F-201-2-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-16)
    - Capital equipment budget, 1989 - 1992; F-201-2-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-16)
    - Five-year plan and capital planning, vol. 1, 1989 - 1992; F-201-2-1-0-10 (Archival box - standard 201-16)
      Creator's original file classification code: 2.A.2.
    - Five-year plan and capital planning, vol. 2, 1989 - 1992; F-201-2-1-0-11 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
    - Capital budget - general, 1990 - 1995; F-201-2-1-0-12 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
    - Capital budget - general, 1991; F-201-2-1-0-13 (Archival box - standard 201-43)
    - Capital budget, 1996; F-201-2-1-0-14 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
  - Operating budget, 1985 - 1996; F-201-2-2; 9 cm of textual records
    - Operating budget, 1985 - 1986; F-201-2-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
    - Requests for submissions sent to deans / Departments, 1987 - 1989; F-201-2-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
      Creator's original file classification code: 2.B.1.a.
    - Operating budget - general, 1988; F-201-2-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
      Creator's original file classification code: 2.B.1.
    - Operating budget - general, 1989 - 1991; F-201-2-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
    - Operating budget - general, 1991; F-201-2-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
    - Operating budget - general, 1992 - 1994; F-201-2-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
    - Operating budget - general, 1994 - 1996; F-201-2-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
    - Budget reduction, vol. 1, 1995 - 1996; F-201-2-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
    - Budget reduction, vol. 2, 1995 - 1996; F-201-2-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 201-17)
- Academic support departments - correspondence, 1983 - 1998; F-201-3; 4.92 m of textual records; Physical description: includes 16 oversize architectural plans (see sub-sub-series 2 and 11).
  Series consists of records relating to the Associate Vice-President, Academic's reporting relationship to the VP Academic (meetings, consultations, advice); regular meetings with other senior university administrators; supervision of and interactions with the academic-support departments that reported directly the AVP Academic; the AVP Academic's involvement in university space planning; consultations with the SFU Faculty Association (SFUFA) and the Teaching Support Staff Union (TSSU); and participation in various university committees. Records consists predominantly of correspondence, reports, and meeting agenda, minutes, support papers and notes. For a detailed description of record types, see individual sub-series descriptions.
  Note that after 1994 when the file classification system fell into disuse, the Office of the AVP Academic increasingly relied on the classification category "AVPA - general" for filing records (see series F-201-3-2-1). Accordingly these files becomes more voluminous and cover a wide spectrum of topics.
  Further accruals to the series are expected. See individual sub-series descriptions for an indication of which sub-series are open (further accruals are expected) and which are closed (no further accruals expected).
  - Vice-President, Academic, 1983 - 1997; F-201-3-1; 87 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the Associate Vice-President, Academic's meetings and interactions with the Vice-President, Academic; participation in regular meetings of senior university administrators, including Vice-Presidents, Deans, Chairs, and Directors; and the activities of the Task Force on University Size (1987-1989). Records include correspondence, meeting agendas and minutes, meeting notes, proposals, policies, and reports.
    Further accruals are expected only for sub-sub-series 3 (Administrators, VPs, Deans and Chairs meetings). No further accruals are expected for any other sub-sub-series.
    F-201-1-1-2, Vice-Presidents' meetings (1984-1987).
    F-201-1-1-3, Vice-Presidents' and Deans' meetings (1983-1998).
    - Meetings and correspondence with the Vice-President, Academic, 1987 - 1995; F-201-3-1-1; 13 cm of textual records
      - Ross Saunders / George Ivany meetings, 1987; F-201-3-1-1-1 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.A.2.
      - Ross Saunders / George Ivany meetings, 1988; F-201-3-1-1-2 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
      - Ross Saunders / George Ivany meetings, 1989; F-201-3-1-1-3 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.A.1.
      - Ross Saunders / VPA meetings, 1990 - 1991; F-201-3-1-1-4 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
      - Ross Saunders / VPA meetings and correspondence, 1991; F-201-3-1-1-5 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
      - Ross Saunders / VPA meetings and correspondence, 1991 - 1992; F-201-3-1-1-6 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
      - Associate VP / VP's meetings and correspondence, 1993; F-201-3-1-1-7 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
      - J. Osborne / VP meetings and correspondence, 1994; F-201-3-1-1-8 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
      - J. Osborne / VP meetings and correspondence, 1995; F-201-3-1-1-9 (Archival box - standard 201-18)
    - Deans' meetings, 1983 - 1996; F-201-3-1-2; 52 cm of textual records
      - Deans' meetings, 1983; F-201-3-1-2-1 (Archival box - standard 201-19)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1984; F-201-3-1-2-2 (Archival box - standard 201-19)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1984; F-201-3-1-2-3 (Archival box - standard 201-19)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 3, 1984; F-201-3-1-2-4 (Archival box - standard 201-19)
      - Deans' meetings, 1987; F-201-3-1-2-5 (Archival box - standard 201-19)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1988; F-201-3-1-2-6 (Archival box - standard 201-19)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.A.3.
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1988; F-201-3-1-2-7 (Archival box - standard 201-20)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 3, 1988; F-201-3-1-2-8 (Archival box - standard 201-20)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1989; F-201-3-1-2-9 (Archival box - standard 201-20)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1989; F-201-3-1-2-10 (Archival box - standard 201-20)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1990; F-201-3-1-2-11 (Archival box - standard 201-20)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1990; F-201-3-1-2-12 (Archival box - standard 201-20)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1991 - 1992; F-201-3-1-2-13 (Archival box - standard 201-20)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1991 - 1992; F-201-3-1-2-14 (Archival box - standard 201-21)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1992; F-201-3-1-2-15 (Archival box - standard 201-21)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1992; F-201-3-1-2-16 (Archival box - standard 201-21)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1993; F-201-3-1-2-17 (Archival box - standard 201-21)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1993; F-201-3-1-2-18 (Archival box - standard 201-21)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1994; F-201-3-1-2-19 (Archival box - standard 201-22)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1994; F-201-3-1-2-20 (Archival box - standard 201-22)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 3, 1994; F-201-3-1-2-21 (Archival box - standard 201-22)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1995; F-201-3-1-2-22 (Archival box - standard 201-22)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1995; F-201-3-1-2-23 (Archival box - standard 201-22)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 1, 1996; F-201-3-1-2-24 (Archival box - standard 201-22)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 2, 1996; F-201-3-1-2-25 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
      - Deans' meetings, vol. 3, 1996; F-201-3-1-2-26 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
    - Administrators, VPs, Deans and Chairs meetings, 1986 - 1997; F-201-3-1-3; 16 cm of textual records
      - Administrators' meetings, 1986 - 1988; F-201-3-1-3-1 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.A.4.
      - VPs, Deans and Chairs meetings, 1986 - 1991; F-201-3-1-3-2 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
      - Directors' meetings, vol. 1, 1988 - 1989; F-201-3-1-3-3 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.A.8.
      - Directors' meetings, vol. 2, 1988 - 1989; F-201-3-1-3-4 (Archival box - standard 201-43)
      - Chairs' meetings, 1988 - 1992; F-201-3-1-3-5 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
      - New Chairs' orientation, 1990 - 1992; F-201-3-1-3-6 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
      - New Administrators' orientation, 1990 - 1993; F-201-3-1-3-7 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
      - Administrators' meetings, 1991 - 1992; F-201-3-1-3-8 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
      - Administrators' meetings, 1993; F-201-3-1-3-9 (Archival box - standard 201-43)
      - Administrators / Chairs meetings, 1994; F-201-3-1-3-10 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
      - Administrators / Chairs meetings, 1995; F-201-3-1-3-11 (Archival box - standard 201-23)
      - Chairs / Administrators' meetings, 1996; F-201-3-1-3-12 (Archival box - standard 201-24)
      - Administrators / Chairs meetings, 1997; F-201-3-1-3-13 (Archival box - standard 201-24)
    - Task Force on University Size (TFUS), 1987 - 1989; F-201-3-1-4; 6 cm of textual records
      Task Force on University Size
      - Task Force on University Size (TFUS), 1987 - 1989; F-201-3-1-4-1 (Archival box - standard 201-24)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.A.6.
      - TFUS - correspondence and working papers, vol. 1, 1988; F-201-3-1-4-2 (Archival box - standard 201-24)
      - TFUS - correspondence and working papers, vol. 2, 1988; F-201-3-1-4-3 (Archival box - standard 201-24)
      - TFUS - correspondence and working papers, vol. 3, 1988; F-201-3-1-4-4 (Archival box - standard 201-24)
  - Associate Vice-President, Academic, 1983 - 1998; F-201-3-2; 2.57 m of textual records and other material; Physical description: includes 11 oversize architectural plans (sub-sub-series 2).
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the activities of the Office carrying out a number of the core responsibilities of the AVP Academic. Activities documented include high-school liaison, IT systems planning, and government liaison; space allocation planning, renovations, and the activities of the University Space Advisory Committee; consultations and negotiations with the Teaching Support Staff Union (TSSU) and the SFU Faculty Association (SFUFA); the AVP Academic's committee work, including chairing of the Committee to Review Personal Safety and Security at SFU (CRPSS) and participation in university computing committees; participation in the British Columbia Council on Admissions and Transfers (BCCAT); the management of legal disputes involving the university, harassment cases, and the development of the university's Harassment Policy; and development of the AVP Academic's file classification system. Records include correspondence, policies, and reports; meeting agenda, minutes, and supporting papers; space inventories, audits, proposals, allocations, agreements, leases, and architectural plans and drawings; legal advice and copies of legal decisions and other court documents; file indices; and notes, drafts, working papers, and printed reference material.
    Further accruals are expected to all sub-sub-series, except for sub-sub-series 5 (Safety Committee) and 6 (University computing committees).
    - Associate Vice-President, Academic - general, 1983 - 1998; F-201-3-2-1; 1.09 m of textual records
      - High school liaison, vol. 1, 1983 - 1987; F-201-3-2-1-1 (Archival box - standard 201-24)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.3.
      - High school liaison, vol. 2, 1983 - 1987; F-201-3-2-1-2 (Archival box - standard 201-24)
      - High school liaison, vol. 3, 1983 - 1987; F-201-3-2-1-3 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
      - Buy-outs, 1984 - 1996; F-201-3-2-1-4 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
      - Social affairs, 1985 - 1986; F-201-3-2-1-5 (Archival box - standard 201-69)
        Creator's original file classification code: Misc. 4.
      - AVPA - general, 1985 - 1987; F-201-3-2-1-6 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.1.a.
      - Student recruitment, 1985 - 1987; F-201-3-2-1-7 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.4.
      - Canadian International Development Agency (CIDA) - Indonesian delegation, 1986; F-201-3-2-1-8 (Archival box - standard 201-69)
        Creator's original file classification code: Misc. 8.
      - Ministry of Education - Funds for Excellence in Education (FEE), 1986; F-201-3-2-1-9 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
      - Student exchanges, 1986; F-201-3-2-1-10 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
      - Work study project, 1986 - 1987; F-201-3-2-1-11 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.9.
      - AVPA - general, 1986 - 1988; F-201-3-2-1-12 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
      - Private BC Colleges and Tranfer Credit Committee, 1986 - 1989; F-201-3-2-1-13 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.5.
      - Project Prometheus, 1987; F-201-3-2-1-14 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.7.
      - AVPA - general, 1988 - 1989; F-201-3-2-1-15 (Archival box - standard 201-46)
      - AUCE grievance, 1988 - 1989; F-201-3-2-1-16 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
      - Access, 1989; F-201-3-2-1-17 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.12.
      - Joint Advisory and Planning Committee, 1989; F-201-3-2-1-18 (Archival box - standard 201-69)
        Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: 3.B.9.
      - AVPA - general, 1989 - 1991; F-201-3-2-1-19 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
      - Faculty Administrative System (FAS), vol. 1, 1989 - 1991; F-201-3-2-1-20 (Archival box - standard 201-69)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.1.s.
      - Faculty Administrative System (FAS), vol. 2, 1989 - 1991; F-201-3-2-1-21 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
      - Awards and fellowships, 1990; F-201-3-2-1-22 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
      - Task Force on Quality of Service Implementation Committee, 1990 - 1991; F-201-3-2-1-23 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
      - Orientation Project Committee, 1990 - 1992; F-201-3-2-1-24 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
      - Employment equity history, vol. 1, 1990 - 1996; F-201-3-2-1-25 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
        Open
      - Employment equity history, vol. 2, 1990 - 1996; F-201-3-2-1-26 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
      - SFU / Burnaby Centennial Committee, 1991; F-201-3-2-1-27 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.11.
      - Software develop - Pacific Gate, 1991; F-201-3-2-1-28 (Archival box - standard 201-69)
        Creator's original file classification code: Misc. E.
      - AVPA - general, 1992; F-201-3-2-1-29 (Archival box - standard 201-25)
      - AVPA - miscellaneous, 1992; F-201-3-2-1-30 (Archival box - standard 201-26)
      - AVPA - miscellaneous, 1992 - 1993; F-201-3-2-1-31 (Archival box - standard 201-26)
      - AVPA - miscellaneous, 1992 - 1993; F-201-3-2-1-32 (Archival box - standard 201-26)
      - Pending, 1992 - 1994; F-201-3-2-1-33 (Archival box - standard 201-69)
      - AVPA - general, 1993; F-201-3-2-1-34 (Archival box - standard 201-26)
      - Graduate students, 1993 - 1994; F-201-3-2-1-35 (Archival box - standard 201-26)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.10.
      - Administrative and Professional Staff Association (APSA), 1994; F-201-3-2-1-36 (Archival box - standard 201-26)
      - Administrative and Professional Staff Association (APSA), 1994; F-201-3-2-1-37 (Archival box - standard 201-26)
      - AVPA - general, vol. 1, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-38 (Archival box - standard 201-27)
      - AVPA - general, vol. 2, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-39 (Archival box - standard 201-27)
      - AVPA - general, vol. 3, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-40 (Archival box - standard 201-27)
      - AVPA - general, vol. 4, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-41 (Archival box - standard 201-27)
      - Ministry of Education Steering Committee, vol. 1, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-42 (Archival box - standard 201-27)
        Creator's original file classification code: 3.B.16.
      - Ministry of Education Steering Committee, vol. 2, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-43 (Archival box - standard 201-27)
      - Ministry of Education Steering Committee, vol. 3, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-44 (Archival box - standard 201-28)
      - AVPA - miscellaneous, vol. 1, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-45 (Archival box - standard 201-28)
      - AVPA - miscellaneous, vol. 2, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-46 (Archival box - standard 201-28)
      - AVPA - miscellaneous, vol. 3, 1994; F-201-3-2-1-47 (Archival box - standard 201-28)